# **Faiq Naufal**

# Front End Developer

faignaufal.com

Phone: +62 813-8064-4229
Email: me@faignaufal.com

Github: github.com/faiq-naufal

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/faiqnaufal

#### CAREER OBJECTIVE

Faiq has experience in web design/web platform development, has a strong understanding of frontend development, and have a good sense of design that will help you produce high-quality solutions for user, bring a deep understanding of modern web and application development, develop functional, reliable, usable, and interactive experiences to the user. Faiq has knowledge of using component-based library such as React and other libraries that help the development process of the application. Faiq is also interested in web optimization, SEO, core web vitals, web performance, any things that will make your user happy and feel satisfied.

#### EXPERIENCES

# **Software Developer Intern**

Internship, Fabelio (PT Tiga Elora Nusantara)

Mar 2021 – Jun 2021 · 3 months · Jakarta

Responsible for maintaining, building additional features and improving core web vitals at fabelio.com which focused on three aspects of the user experience: loading time (LCP), interactivity time (FID), and visual stability (CLS). These aspects affected the performance score, google search ranking, and total good URLs. Collaborated with other developers, QA, and team lead using Scrum workflow. Responsible to create pull request to be reviewed by other team members, and to review other members code and pull request.

Started reducing project's bundle size by replacing third-party packages with native JavaScript approach, delay loading components that weren't shown on page load, preventing unnecessary module import, and separating desktop and mobile components to improve page load time. Ensuring dynamically displayed components and images need to have reserved space to improve visual stability and reduce layout shifting.

Reduced 10.6% page load time and 26.6% page download time. Improved overall ecommerce conversation rate from 0.71% to 0.95% and desktop channel conversation rate from 1.44% to 2.13% on Google Analytics reports.

## Front-End Developer Intern

Internship, Logique Digital Indonesia

Feb 2019 - Feb 2020 · 1 year · Jakarta

Worked closely with design, content, and developer team to build and deliver static and dynamic web-based solutions based on client requirements and client requests.

Had responsibility to build front-end solutions in the form of desktop and mobile sites and needed to finish and deliver the changes or the full works within the time given.

Built websites from scratch, maintained existing project by updating the design and content, implemented seo techniques and contents using HTML meta tags, Google Analytics, JSON-LD schema based on requirements from digital marketing team, sliced assets from PSD, AI, Zeplin or Abstract given by the designer team. Handled multiple project at the same time and had responsibility to report back.

Had successfully managed more than 15+ client's website projects, contributed to increased revenue and portfolios of the company, gained a lot of experiences building various types of websites.

#### ORGANIZATION

#### **Information System Project Member (ISPM)**

Information System Laboratory Binus University

Feb 2018 – Feb 2019 · 1 year · Jakarta

- An extracurricular activity focused on improving students on coding and app development.
- Responsible to work as a team, to build web-based projects from scratch, to join competitions representing my university.
- Learnt and built website projects, joined a competition called ItechnoCup with my team.
- Got 3<sup>rd</sup> place award on ItechnoCup web development competition 2018.

#### INDUSTRY KNOWLEDGE

Front-End Development, Web Design/Development, Mobile-First Responsive Design, Cross-Browser Development, Web Performance, Progressive Web App, JamStack.

# HARD SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript ES6+, React.js, Next.js, Bootstrap, jQuery, Styled Components, Tailwind CSS, Material UI, Git, Ajax, Redux, Babel, Webpack, Figma, Slicing UI, Data Fetching (REST, GraphQL), Debugging.

### SOFT SKILLS

Collaboration, Teamwork, Personal Development, Interpersonal, Growth Mindset, Eager to Learn, Can-Do Attitude, Problem Solving, Flexibility, Good Sense of UI/UX and Design.

#### EDUCATION

#### Bachelor of Science in Information Systems · GPA: 3.58

Binus University

Sep 2016 - Sep 2020 · 4 years · Jakarta

#### AWARD

ItechnoCup Web Development Competition Award Certificate (2018)